[theme music playing]
They had us slaughtered
like we were animals.
Is that why you came back here?
To get back at my family?
Ivy, seeking revenge won't solve anything.
It'll only be harder on you.
If you don't tell me
where Miss Ivy Aguas is,
you'll see what I'm capable of.
I need to find out who filed
the police report against Raul.
[Belen] He kidnapped Jasmin.
Do you know what Jasmin's full name is?
A woman I spoke to called her Camia.
[Raul] Camia's gone, she dead!
Isn't that what you want to hear?
Why are you so obsessed with her?
Because I love Camia.
I need to bury her back
in the grave she crawled out of!
If it weren't for your womanizing,
none of this would've happened
to Lily or our family!
What family? You aren't related
to the Ardientes.
Emilia's not your real mother.
Camia Cruz, a woman Mom killed
a long time ago.
She's still alive.
Killing is the only thing you know,
and yet, you still fail.
I will fix this problem, Papa.
I will fix this problem myself.
You can't look for her.
First of all, you have no machinery.
Let me make my own machinery.
Take me to Ivy Aguas.
I need to be ready in case
Emilia figures us out.
Books and other stuff.
They might help jog your memories, Mom.
Dante… Lily, my daughter…
My daughter… Lily…
[tense music playing]
Was that Arnaldo's car
I heard leaving just then?
Yes, Congressman.
How curious…
He didn't tell me he was going.
[panting]
Mom, do you remember Dad?
Yes. Yes.
I remember Dante. He made this.
How about Lily?
-Yes. Yes.
-Really?
I remember Lily.
She's the one in this photo.
Where is she? I want to see her.
-She's here.
-Let me see her.
You're looking at her, Mom.
It's been 13 years already.
I'm not a kid anymore.
I'm all grown up. See? I'm Lily.
No. No.
Thirteen years?
It hasn't been that long yet.
You aren't Lily.
Why can't I remember anything?
Why can't I remember who you are?
Why are we here? What are we doing here?
Why are we hiding? Who are we hiding from?
I'm so confused! Tell me! Why are we here?
I'm sorry for causing you so much trouble.
No, you're not. It's okay, Mom.
Don't blame yourself for what happened.
I'm here to take care of you…
and help you regain your memories.
Please don't force yourself
to remember anything.
It's not your fault, Mom. Take it easy.
Hi. Good morning. Is Miss Aguas here?
Ma'am, I'm sorry,
but we aren't allowed to accept
any visitors at the moment.
Look, we aren't your typical guests.
This is a courtesy call from the mayor.
And the former governor
of Poblacion Ardiente.
Didn't I tell you
I won't entertain any guests?
Ma'am, I'm sorry. They're
just really persistent.
Courtesy call from the mayor.
I'll just ask them to leave, ma'am.
No, now you can't do that!
They'll suspect something.
I'm really sorry, ma'am.
Okay, just tell them to wait.
-You know what to do.
-Yes, ma'am.
[suspenseful music playing]
Mom, let's move, okay?
To a nicer room. Here, Mom.
Mom…
I'm sorry, but can you
please stay here awhile?
I'll just attend to some guests.
Um, please stay here. Don't go out, okay?
But we're not done reading yet.
I know, Mom. Here.
Feel free to read these while I'm away.
Don't worry. I'll be back soon.
This won't take long, okay?
Go on, read them.
Nurse.
Listen carefully.
Do everything you can to make
my mother stay calm, okay?
Everything you need, including
reading materials, food,
and medicine, are all in there.
Don't let her go out.
Lock the door, okay?
No one else must see her.
Oh, my! What's taking her so long?
We're going in now, okay?
Ma'am, wait…
We're going in. Can you
get out of my way, please?
-Excuse me.
-Ma'am, wait, ma'am.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Now go back inside.
[suspenseful music playing]
Ma'am, wait… Ma'am.
Thank you. Isn't she ready yet?
-Please wait here, ma'am.
-Yeah.
[suspenseful music playing]
Ma'am, they're waiting outside.
You know what to do.
They must not see my mother.
-There's no room for mistakes!
-Yes, ma'am.
Ma'am, sir, Miss Aguas can see you now.
Wow! Finally.
-This way, please.
-Arnaldo, let's go.
Thank you.
Ivy!
-Emilia!
-Long time no see!
-Mr. Mayor.
-Miss Aguas.
What a pleasant surprise.
[smooches]
You have a beautiful house.
No wonder you haven't
come back to Ardiente.
Are you here to take me back?
Arnaldo, get us a bottle
of wine from the bar.
Ivy and I have some business to discuss.
-Okay.
-Thanks.
Actually, Ivy,
I need something else from you.
Well…
I need funding…
for my future endeavor.
-Future endeavor?
-Yes.
For my return as governor.
You know what I mean.
Emilia, I need a more convincing pitch.
Well, I'll go straight to the point, Ivy.
I need a huge sum of money
to get back into power
and stop my enemies' plans against me.
Like this one person.
I don't know if you're familiar with her.
Camia Cruz?
[dramatic music playing]
-[Tonio] Hey!
-[Camia crying]
Lily… Run! Run!
Lily…
I got separated from her.
I told her to run.
Camia Cruz?
Doesn't ring a bell.
Besides, what's in it for me, Emilia?
Why would I invest in something…
or someone who's bankrupt
and lost everything?
Ivy, I may have fallen now.
But you know? I will rise again.
I don't want to leave you behind
while I'm on top.
[suspenseful sting]
[laughs]
Was that a joke?
Oh, I'm sorry, I thought it was a joke.
I'm… I'm so sorry for laughing, Emilia.
[laughs]
Well, just so you know,
I'm the only Ardiente
who'll work with you.
There is a witch-hunt ongoing,
and you're first on Papa's list.
It's okay. It's really fine.
I'm not afraid of the congressman.
You know, Ivy, you may not
need me now, but soon, you will.
[slow handclaps]
Bravo, Emilia. That was a good pitch.
-Does that mean we have a deal?
-Of course, we have a deal.
[both chuckle]
What do you want?
Do you know just how
much trouble you've caused?
You and your women are the root
of this family's problems.
And now, I have to find and bury someone…
who should've died a long time ago.
What are you talking about?
Get your hands off me!
We're just talking! What is this about?!
And your son, Diego?
He doesn't deserve
to carry the Ardiente name.
He's always ruining my plans.
But he should be thankful
I'm a good person.
If I weren't, I would've
told him the truth years ago.
What do you want to say to my son?
You know? Wait!
Whatever it is, I already told him.
So, if you have something to
say, say it to me!
I'm the father,
and you can't even face me!
-We'll see.
-Then get up!
Stop hiding behind your bodyguards.
-Hit him hard.
-Are you scared?
[groans]
[Julio] Oh! Wait!
Beat him up, but don't touch his face.
I don't want people to see him
and figure out he's been injured.
Just hit his body. Do it!
[grunts and groans]
[panting]
Look at what you've done to my floor.
How dare you stain it
with your dirty blood!
Why, what's the matter?
Hmm? You think you can
bring me down with this?
Well, you're wrong.
You can't knock me down.
And you know that.
That's why this is all you can do to me!
Right? You can't take me!
But you know what?
It'd be better if you just killed me,
Papa.
[tense music playing]
One bottle of wine…
Ivy?
-She's outside, Miss Camia.
-I want to see Ivy.
I need to tell her something.
But Miss Ivy said we can't go outside.
Thank you.
-I'll take care of you here.
-No, I need to talk to her now.
Miss Camia. Miss Camia, she'll be here--
Let go of me! I just want to talk to Ivy.
-Miss Camia…
-Ouch! Ouch. Stop it!
-Let go of me!
-[loud thud]
What's that sound?
Mom?
-Miss Camia…
-Let go…
Miss Ivy will come back.
-I just want to talk to Ivy.
-She'll come back for you.
[tense music playing]
Why are there nurses?
Maybe one of the guests is sick.
Wait, a guest?
Isn't this resort temporarily closed?
I'm not sure, sir. Excuse me.
Ivy, wait…
Ivy will come back here.
-I need to see her.
-I told you…
-I want to talk to her.
-Miss Ivy will be here soon.
Mr. Mayor.
Do you need anything?
-What's a nurse doing here?
-Oh…
I've been feeling under
the weather these past few days,
so I called for a nurse and a doctor.
Let's go?
But, you know, what's that noise?
Oh, right. Can you
please wait for me outside?
I'll just check on it.
It might've been the wind.
The breeze gets pretty strong here.
-Oh, okay.
-Ria? Ria?
-Yes, ma'am?
-Did something fall?
Was it because of the wind again?
Oh yes, ma'am! It's very windy
outside so something fell again.
-Then fix it, please.
-Yes, ma'am.
I told you, it's really windy
in this resort.
-Let's go?
-Okay…
[tense music playing]
Now, it's becoming clear to me.
Miss Aguas gave this land to
the farmers to win their trust.
Miss Aguas is giving them the illusion…
that they have rights and power
over the land and their lives.
And I can't let them believe in that.
Because worker ants don't have
the right to govern themselves.
I need to put them back in their place.
Like the slaves they are.
So, what's your plan now, Congressman?
I'll remind them I'm still
the ruler of this town.
And I will need your help, William.
Bye, Ivy. Thanks again.
-So, it's a deal?
-Yes, of course, Emilia.
-Great! Thank you.
-Drive safe.
As long as you're indebted to me…
you are now my slave, Emilia.
We're really sorry, Governor Alvarez.
We really don't know where Miss Ivy is.
And it's impossible for us to hide her.
Yes, we know she bought us land,
but we remain loyal to the Ardientes!
[chuckles] You liars!
Go! Search the area!
-Hang on! Sir, wait!
-No, sir! No!
[people clamoring]
Why are you doing this to us?!
You can't do this to us!
I am the governor!
And that's what you get for being a rebel!
-Don't hurt her!
-This isn't right!
If you want to punish us,
do it the right way!
-You've got some nerve! Fine!
-No, Governor!
-Take her!
-Governor, stop! Please!
Please stop! Don't hurt
my daughter! Take me, instead!
You're really annoying me. Take him too!
-Wait!
-Listen carefully!
From now on, this cooperative is closed!
All your things and your produce
belong to us! Go!
Seize everything here!
-What about our livelihood?!
-You all need to learn a lesson!
[people clamoring]
Mom?
Mom, I'm here.
Why did you leave me, Ivy?
Mom, I told you I had
some visitors, but I'm here now.
You left me. Why did you leave me?
Mom, don't cry.
It's okay.
-Dad!
-Let go of my daughter!
Let go of my daughter!
Shut up! Do you want to suffer
like your dad?
Fernan! Fernan!
[William] Take them!
[people clamoring]
-Five, four, three…
-[people clamoring]
Nimfa! Nimfa!
…two, one.
-[William] Punish them! Go on!
-Now.
-Governor.
-Congressman.
I'm asking you to please stop
what you're doing for a second.
Thank you.
The people of Ardiente,
my beloved children.
We here at Poblacion Ardiente
are like one huge family.
A family that loves each other.
But sometimes, when someone gets unruly…
they need to be punished.
Why is Governor Alvarez punishing you?
This is not only for you
to hand over Ivy Aguas…
but for you to learn a lesson
for refusing to obey.
You doubted the Ardiente
family's capability…
to properly govern this town.
The moment you got your own land,
you thought you could live
by your own rules.
Therefore, I'll make you feel…
what it's like to own land
without the government's support.
From now on,
I'll close down the cooperative
and cut the supply of water,
so you'll know…
-No!
-how difficult it is to live
without the government's support!
No, Señor Julio!
Where are you taking that?!
[people clamoring]
Congressman, please forgive us.
We won't do it again.
-Dad…
-We'll return the land.
Fernan!
You know…
this punishment is for your own good.
This is a lesson.
Believe it or not,
it truly hurts me to do this.
But, like a parent…
if their children don't behave…
they have to be disciplined,
even if it hurts.
One day, you'll thank me.
This is proof of my love for you.
-Dad! Dad!
-Nimfa!
Dad.
[tense music playing]
Did you see how I toyed
with the people of Ardiente?
How are you able to get them
to agree to whatever you say?
I know how those peasants' minds work.
So predictable.
Ivy Aguas is mistaken.
She is so wrong.
These people cannot be empowered.
Even if you give them
the title of the land…
they're still stupid, ignorant slaves…
who cannot think for themselves.
Ah…
Oh, well. Our good deed
for the day is done.
Let's have lunch. Your treat.
Let's go. Drive on.
Where are we going to look for Miss Ivy?
Poor Fernan.
When will Julio Ardiente give us a break?
This isn't right.
He's not a father, he's a dictator.
Diego?
[panting]
I'm not a real Ardiente.
Emilia isn't my real mother.
-What?
-Diego. Diego, wait. Diego!
Diego, listen to us!
Listen to us.
Remember, we're here for you.
And we love you more than anyone else.
[tense music playing]
[Pandoy] Diego, where are you going?
We've tried every treatment possible,
but you can see
how Camia's brain function
continues to degenerate.
Have you decided if she'll undergo ECT?
While we may not be sure
she'll get better, at least
we tried everything before
going to the US for treatment.
Then again, miracles can happen.
Dad? Where's my mother?
Dad, please, answer me.
Where's my real mother? I want to see her.
Diego, I'm sorry, but that won't happen.
You can't see your mother.
What do you mean? Dad…
-Dad, please.
-Diego, I know this is hard.
But there's nothing I can do.
You can't see her because…
your mother's gone.
Emilia had her killed.
[suspenseful sting]
No.
No. That can't be. My mom isn't dead.
Son…
She's been dead for years.
Emilia had her killed.
I'm sorry I wasn't able to do anything.
I wasn't able to protect your mother.
It's my fault. I'm sorry.
No. No, Dad.
Don't blame yourself. It's not your fault.
If there's anyone who needs to pay…
for everything that happened to us,
to you, me, and your mother…
it's Emilia and Julio.
The Ardientes.
Mom, I agreed to do the procedure.
Just like what Dad said…
Learn to fight.
Learn to take risks.
And learn to have faith.
[Ivy] I love you and Dad so much.
And the love I feel for you…
gives me strength…
to keep fighting…
to keep believing.
Mom, I believe you'll get better.
You'll recover.
You'll get better…
because we still have to win this fight.
-[heart beating]
-[machine beeping rhythmically]
[Dante] Once we settle
in Poblacion Ardiente…
I'll build my own private law firm.
[Camia] Me too, hon. I'll put up
a weekend daycare center.
-Dante? Dante!
-[Dante grunting]
-What happened…
-Lily… Run!
[groans]
I thought you were dead,
but you're alive, Mom!
It's me, Lily.
-Lily?
-You're looking at her, Mom.
It's been 13 years already.
I'm not a kid anymore.
I'm all grown up. See? I'm Lily.
[tense music playing]
[solemn music playing]
Mom.
How are you feeling?
Ivy.
[pants]
Lily…
Lily.
My Lily.
-Mom?
-Lily, is it?
Lily. My daughter.
-Mom?
-My Lily.
-Mom.
-My Lily…
-Mom…
-You're all grown up.
What happened?
Look at you.
You're all grown up.
Do you remember me now?
Yes.
Do you remember me now, Mom?
My daughter…
So much… So much has happened.
I'll tell you everything.
It's a long story, but…
Can I hold you?
-Yes.
-You remember me!
["Wildflower" by Arnel Pineda playing]
Mom…
-I love you so much!
-I love you too.
I love you so much, Mom.
[sobbing]
You remember me now!
Ivy.
Nanny Carlotta! My mom remembers me again!
This is the moment I've been waiting for.
[sobs]
She's alive!
Mom.
This is Nanny Carlotta.
All those years we were apart…
Nanny Carlotta took care of me.
[Camia] Thank you.
Doc… Doc, thank you!
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you so much!
I must admit, that in my
whole medical career,
this is the first time
I've witnessed someone respond this fast
to the treatment and recovery.
It's a miracle!
Thank you very much, Doctor.
You should thank your daughter, Ivy.
She never gave up.
Doc, my mother will only
keep getting better, right?
We will continue her medication
and therapy.
And I believe that with your
continued love and support,
there's a huge chance
for her full recovery.
Thank you.
Really, thank you.
Mom.
Mom. I love you.
-I love you too, Lily.
-I love you, Mom.
I love you very much.
You mean everything to me.
Diego…
-Diego, where are you going?
-Diego!
-Nanny, please let go of me.
-Answer us, Diego!
-Why won't you talk to us?
-What's your problem? Diego!
Answer your Nanny Loring, Diego!
I have something to take care of!
And what would that be?!
Nanny, Uncle, for once…
-can't you just leave me be?!
-Why--
You won't leave until you
tell us what happened!
Pandoy!
You might get yourself in
danger! Do you understand?!
-What's happening to you?!
-What's the problem?!
They killed my mother!
There, I said it! They killed my mom.
Dad told me Emilia had my real mom killed.
-I'll make them pay!
-Diego! Diego!
Diego, you won't leave here
until you calm down. Do you understand?
-What should I do, then?!
-Diego!
You'll only get
yourself hurt if you do that!
So I should I just wait and do nothing?!
-Diego…
-They killed my mom!
She didn't do anything wrong!
She just loved Dad. Where's the justice?
Why do we let the Ardientes
treat us like this?!
-Listen to me.
-When will we do something?!
-Listen to me first.
-Pandoy! Pandoy!
-They will kill you!
The Ardientes will kill you!
Don't you get it?
The Ardientes will kill you…
-Pandoy!
-if you go against them!
Pandoy!
[Loring cries]
Diego…
Diego. If you still respect me
as your second father…
you'll listen to me.
You won't pick a fight with the Ardientes!
-I won't let them kill you too.
-Pandoy!
Pandoy. Diego! Pandoy!
Diego…
[yowls]
[somber music playing]
How are you, Mom?
Lily, I remember everything now.
The moment your dad died…
the things they did to me…
until the day we got separated.
I remember now.
Like it happened yesterday.
[exhales sharply]
Lily, I know you're angry and hurt
because I feel that way too.
But I want to help you.
I want to know what happened
after your father and I lost you.
How you became Ivy Aguas.
It's all because of Miss Prianka.
She's how I became Ivy Aguas.
She took me in. She helped and taught me…
to fight the Ardientes.
If it weren't for Miss Prianka,
I'd probably be dead by now.
Then I'm grateful to her.
But as your mother…
I should tell you not to seek vengeance.
That you must learn to forgive.
[exhales] But then…
that'd make me a hypocrite.
Because I can't forgive them, either.
I understand why you'd want
revenge on the Ardientes.
But I'm just worried about your safety.
You have nothing to worry about.
What's important is that we're safe.
And I'll do everything…
I'll do everything, Mom.
Are you still planning to seek revenge?
Mom… We'll talk about
that some other time.
Get some rest for now.
I want to visit your father's grave.
I want to see him.
Mom, for now…
this ring will have to do.
Because I can't let you
go back to Poblacion Ardiente.
If they find out you're alive,
I'm sure they'll have you killed.
I won't let that happen.
I won't lose you all over again.
What the Ardientes
are doing to us isn't right.
They're walking all over us!
How do we get our land back?
-What's going on here?
-Diego…
Nimfa, Mr. Fernan, what happened?
Governor Alvarez confiscated
our rice and money
and closed down the cooperative.
What?
It's a good thing Señor Julio came.
If not, things could've been worse.
The Congressman spoke to Governor.
But they still have our money and crops.
What was the point of it?
I'm sure the Ardientes
have something to do with this.
The congressman is a fraud.
They'll do anything to get our land.
How could you say that
about your own family?
I'm not trying to ruin them.
I'm just telling the truth.
The Ardientes were never on our side.
I won't ever let anyone,
especially the Ardientes,
hurt you and our family.
No matter what.
[man] We all know they're
taking advantage of us.
But can we do something about it?
We can.
But we don't need to resort to violence.
We'll do this the right way. Legally.
Legally? Is this legal?
That's nonsense, Diego.
We have to abide by the law.
The Ardientes are the law in this place!
They hurt my daughter.
Should I wait for them
to massacre my family
before I make a move?
It's only fair that
we should fight fire with fire.
[all] He's right.
Give them a taste of their own medicine.
-They've gone too far.
-Fernan is right.
We're being played.
[Ivy] I promise you, Mom.
The Ardientes will all burn in hell.
I'll take away their power…
until they crawl in the mud
where they belong.
I swear it.
-Nanny Carlotta.
-Ivy.
-Ivy, come in.
-Where are the--
Ivy, where's your mother?
She's in her room, resting.
Ivy, I'm so happy for you.
I know what you had to go through
before finding your mother.
Nanny, all I'm hoping for now
is that we'll always be together.
I hope we can live a happy and quiet life.
Wait, you must be tired from the drive.
-Have something to drink.
-Thank you.
[phone rings]
[phone ringing]
It's Jepoy.
Jepoy?
Hello, Ivy.
Did the Governor track you down?
Yes, Emilia found us.
But she doesn't know anything.
She didn't see my mom.
And she should think twice
about ratting me out
if she doesn't want me to reveal
her plans against her father.
But you still need to be careful, Ivy.
The congressman's still
looking for you. He suspects…
that the farmers you helped
are protecting you.
Wait. Do you know
what he did to the farmers?
-No, why?
-Ivy, you're not going to like
what the congressman did to them.
He shut down the cooperative.
He confiscated all the farmers' money and…
produce to punish them.
Diego…
If you think Pandoy and I
will give you our blessing
to fight the Ardientes, you're mistaken.
I will accept any difficulty
that will come my way.
I'll bow down before them if I have to…
as long as they don't hurt you.
Governor Alvarez is a puppet.
I'm sure the congressman ordered
him to punish the farmers.
Ivy, don't… Stay out of this.
You're with your mother now.
Think about your safety.
You're right, Nanny Carlotta.
I need to prioritize my mother's safety.
You're right.
Here's what we'll do.
You and Mom will go
to our house in Manila.
We'll double our security there.
What about you? Aren't you coming too?
I'm not coming, my fight against
the Ardientes isn't over.
I have to fulfill my promise
to the people of Poblacion Ardiente.
And I still have to seek justice
for my father's death.
I don't make promises that I can't keep.
Ivy… I'm only thinking about your safety.
Don't put yourself in harm's way.
Thank you for your concern,
Nanny Carlotta.
But nothing's going to change.
My decision is final.
So, tomorrow, you're going to Manila.
-Ivy--
-Please look after my mother.
Take care of her.
[Ivy] Mom?
Tomorrow, you and Nanny Carlotta
are going to Manila.
You'll stay in my house?
Our house in Manila.
Do you want to teach again, Mom?
There are a lot of schools near our house.
What about you?
Mom…
I have to stay here
because there's something
I need to settle.
Here? Or in Ardiente?
Mom.
Don't worry about me.
I can take care of myself.
Once I'm done with what I need to do,
I'll go to Manila too. I promise. Okay?
-Pandoy!
-Loring?
-What's wrong?
-Pandoy! It's Diego!
-What about him?
-Diego left.
He might've gone to the Ardientes!
-What?!
-[phone chimes]
Who's that?
-It's Diego.
-What?
[Diego] Nanny, Uncle…
please forgive me
for what I'm about to do.
I will never have peace
until I confront the people
who murdered my mother.
In case I'm not able to return,
let's just accept that it's my fate.
Please leave Ardiente
and don't ever come back.
Don't do anything that may
put your lives in danger.
And always remember that I love you both.
[sobs]
Thank you for taking care of me…
and giving me a home and a family.
Two things the Ardientes deprived me of.
[tense music playing]
Did you have my real mother killed?
-Diego!
-What are you going to do?!
This family raised you,
and this is how you repay us?!
Papa!
Now, drive!
I'll make you feel just
how much you deserve to suffer.
How could you let this
happen to your son?!
[Fernan] They showed us violence,
and violence is what we'll give them back.
[grunting]
If you're going to fight the Ardientes,
then I won't let you go alone.
I'll fight with you.
Attorney, what can you say
to the Ardientes?
[lawyer] We're coming for all of you.
[Emilia] Who's behind this?
[theme music playing]